Mobile: 0745 095 1306

richard.smith.67@gmail.com

## Profile

An experienced C#.NET developer with a good practical understanding of software development design principles.

I enjoy exploring emerging software technologies/best practices and have considerable experience developing new applications as well as maintaining/enhancing legacy applications.

I strive to write clean, maintainable code and enjoy the discovery process in writing new software.

## **Core Skills**

- **Development Tools:** Microsoft Visual Studio (2003-19), Microsoft Code, VSTS, Fiddler, Postman, Sql Server Management Studio, Chrome Developer Tools, NUnit
- Databases: Sql Server, Mongo, Entity Framework
- Source Control: Git, TFS, Azure DevOps
- Patterns And Principles: SOLID, Clean Code
- Analysis And Design: Analysis of business and system processes, dealing directly with users and business analysts, production of design documents
- Languages: C#, Javascript, HTML, CSS
- Frameworks: Microsoft ASP/Web Api, some experience of React/Angular

# **Work History**

### Software Developer - Clevermed Ltd, Edinburgh (January 2014 - Present)

Clevermed provides SAAS patient data management software for the healthcare sector in the UK and Australia/New Zealand.

#### Responsibilities

- Development and maintenance of Clevermed's main pregnancy care desktop application. This is primarily a Microsoft windows forms/html application connecting to a SQL server backend via SOAP web services.
- Involved in design and development of an automated servicing and payroll system for New Zealand community midwives. Interfacing via HL7 messaging, development of several windows services, client and server-side development, creating reports, generating pdfs and invoices.
- Developed a web api to allow integration of third party patient data with Clevermed core data.
- Developed a web api to hook into Clevermed service desk via a mobile app. Api allows users to browse and update service desk entries, chat in real time and display various stats.

## Software Developer - Standard Life, Edinburgh (2001 - March 2013)

Involved in the design, development, testing and implementation of numerous C# .NET/VB6 applications for internal business use.

## **Projects**

- Maturities Enhancement task server component C#: Developed a component used to integrate with ICR/OCR (Intelligent/Optical Character Recognition Software) letter scan. Used for routing work to appropriate Business Departments via IBM Automated Work Distributor (AWD).
- CAT (Cancel and Transfer) task server component C#: Developed a component used to cancel and transfer bulk agencies (i.e. cancel an old agency and transfer all agents to a new one), update mainframe systems and issue documentation.
- LPAS (Life and Pensions Administration System) C#: LPAS is a widely used internal customer servicing platform which I helped enhance/maintain.
- Future Settlements task server component C#: Developed a component to capture future retiral details for customers. This component updated all necessary mainframe systems, scheduled tasks and issued timely documentation to the retiree.
- SPICE (Single Platform for an Integrated Customer Experience) Retirals C#: General development. SPICE is one of the main internal servicing platforms used by Standard Life. It uses a shell/plugin type architecture for maximum extensibility.
- **SPICE Agency Alterations plugin C#:** Developed a plugin used by SPICE to transfer a customer and all their relevant details to a new IFA. It updates all systems required to remove the old agent, assign the new one and issue relevant documentation to all parties.
- **Health Claims System MQ, Screen Scraping, VB6, DB2, DP:** Developed an application used to process health claims through from initial contact to settlement.
- AFS (Annuity Futures System) MQ, Screen Scraping, VB6, DB2, DOC1: Developed a system for amalgamating several existing ad-hoc processes into one application to enable more efficient processing of annuity enquiries, payments and letters.

## **Education**

Open University BSc 2010: Primarily Maths/Computing Modules

University Of Aberdeen (1984-86): Physics

**Speyside High School:** 3 CSYS, 6 Highers, 7 'O' Grades